mintos.com 2019-05-07

# Privacy Policy

**1\. General terms**

AS Mintos Marketplace, registration number 40103903643, with its registered office at Skanstes iela 50, Riga LV-1013, Latvia, (hereinafter – Mintos) has developed this Privacy Policy to inform persons registered on the Mintos website www.mintos.com (hereinafter – Portal) as its users (hereinafter – User) and who use the services provided by Mintos (hereinafter – Services), on the collection, use and transfer of their personal data to third parties.

Mintos strives to ensure appropriate technical and organisational measures to protect the User’s data and to provide transparent data protection rules. This Privacy Policy outlines the data processing activities carried out by Mintos in respect to Users who are natural persons. This Privacy Policy does not cover those Users who are legal persons.

The personal data processing activities carried out by Mintos can be described not only in this Privacy Policy but also in the Portal User Agreement (hereinafter – Agreement), Assignment Agreement and the Cookies section of the Privacy Policy.

The terms used in the Privacy Policy conform to the terms used in the Agreement insofar as the Privacy Policy does not specify otherwise.

If you have any questions regarding the Privacy Policy of Mintos or if you wish to obtain additional information on how to exercise the rights specified herein, you can contact us by writing an email to [support@mintos.com.](mailto:support@mintos.com) Additional contact information is available in the Portal.

 **2\. Categories of User’s personal data**

Mintos processes the following categories of User’s personal data:

  * User’s Data, including, but not limited to, the User’s full name, gender, date of birth, personal identity number, investor’s ID number, copy of an identity document, User’s bank account number, position grade, area of work, preferred language; 
  * Due diligence data, including, but not limited to,origin of funds, information on the purpose and intended nature of the business relationship, information gained fromrisk assessment-based activities;
  * Contact Information, including the User’s address, country of residence, e-mail address and phone number;
  * Transaction Data, including the User’s invested funds, investments, transactions, incoming payments, claimed disbursements of money, information regarding the concluded assignment agreements, net annual return, selected currency, available funds, accountancy accounts;
  * Communication Data, including the User’s communication with Mintos through the Portal via live chat, via email and/or by phone.  

 **3\. Purposes of processing personal data**

If the User fails to provide the personal data when processing of such data is necessary to enter into and fulfil the Agreement or required by statute, Mintos cannot provide the Services.

3.1. Use of cookies

The Portal uses cookies to maintain and improve the operation of the Portal. Information on the use of cookies is available at [Cookie Privacy Policy](https://www.mintos.com/en/cookie-policy/).

3.2. Providing Services to the User

Upon submission of the Registration Application and registration with the Portal, personal data of the User is used to enter into the Agreement and create the Virtual Account to be used as a means to receive the Services.

For all of the sub-purpose specified below, the User’s data is processed by Mintos and our cooperation partners that provide servers, IT, accounting, communication, bank, CRM services and/or other subjects as stipulated in Clause 13.3. of the Agreement (please see section “Transfer of information to third parties” for further information). 

3.2.1. Identifying the User and concluding the Agreement

In order to identify the User and conclude the Agreement, the User’s Data, Contact Information, Transaction Data and Communication data is used. Additionally, such data as the date of conclusion is processed as well. Identification of the User is carried out as described in Section 3.3.1. of this Privacy Policy.

This data is necessary to verify the User’s identity, conclude and fulfil the Agreement, communicate with the User regarding the fulfilment of the Agreement. The personal data processing is based on the conclusion and fulfilment of the Agreement and compliance with such legitimate interests of Mintos as informing the User about the activity in the Virtual Account and protection of its rights and interests in case of a dispute as well as to comply with the statutory obligation to keep information on business activities conducted.

3.2.2. Creating and maintaining the Virtual Account

In order to create and maintain the Virtual Account, the User’s Data, Contact Information, Transaction Data and Communication data is used. Additionally, such data as the User’s password is processed as well, however, Mintos, nor our cooperation partners have access to the User’s password.

This data is necessary to provide log in options in the Portal, to communicate with the User in case of any inquiries, to conduct surveys and to ensure a means by which the User can receive the Services. The personal data processing is based on the conclusion and fulfilment of the Agreement and compliance with such legitimate interests of Mintos as maintenance of the Virtual Account, improvement of the Service quality, informing the User about the activity in the Virtual Account and protection of its rights and interests in case of a dispute.

3.2.3. Providing Services

In order to provide Services, the User’s Data, Contact Information and Transaction Data is used.

This data is necessary to verify the User’s identity, conclude and fulfil the Agreement, ensure cash deposits and withdraws, send daily summaries and notices about deposits. The personal data processing is based on the conclusion and fulfilment of the Agreement and compliance with such legitimate interests of Mintos as informing the User about the activity in the Virtual Account and protection of its rights and interests in case of a dispute.

Mintos provides the User with the opportunity to opt-out from receiving certain notices in connection with the Services, such as daily summaries and notices about deposits. The User can choose which notices to receive in the Virtual Account.

3.2.4. Sending registration reminders

In order to provide Services and conclude the Agreement, Mintos can send registration reminders to Users, who have not completed the registration process via e-mail. Mintos may send reminders in the following time intervals – 24 hours, 3 (three) days, 7 (seven) days, 30 (thirty) days, 60 (sixty) days after the registration process has been initiated.

Mintos shall discard the Users registration application and will not continue to send registration reminders to the User if the User does not complete the registration process within 90 (ninety) days from the moment when the registration process has been initiated.

3.3. Enforcement of statutory obligations

In order to fulfil the statutory obligations in the fields of accountancy and anti-money laundering and terrorist financing prevention, Mintos processes the User’s Data, Due diligence data, Communication Data, Contact Information and information specified by the User in the User’s questionnaire in accordance with the provisions of the laws and regulations of the Republic of Latviaand the internal control system of Mintos.

For the purpose specified above, the User’s data is processed by Mintos and our cooperation partners that provide server, IT, User verification and accounting services.

3.3.1. Due diligence

As per the applicable laws and regulations Mintos performs the due diligence of the User, which includes, but is not limited to, to identifying the User and verification of the User’s identity document and processing the Due diligence data. 

Identification of the User and verification of the Users identification document is carried out via a third-party verification portal, which processes the Users data and the Due diligence data. During this process, the User submits a photo and/or video of the Users face and identification document to the verification portal using the specially designed system of the third-party verification portal.

This data processing is based on the necessity to conclude and perform the Agreement and to comply with the legal obligations of Mintos in the field of anti-money laundering and terrorist financing prevention.

3.4. Sending of informational materials

Upon applying for receipt of informational materials the User agrees that User’s Data, Contact Information, and certain Transaction Data (funds invested and incoming payments) is used to prepare an appropriate commercial communication for the User based on the User’s data available to Mintos, using profiling, and to segment the User into a certain category.

Informational materials include any and all communication from Mintos that is not connected to providing Services, the fulfilment of the Agreement or other essential information (such as a notice that the term of the provided personal identity number will expire).

Mintos uses profiling, i.e., automatic means for processing personal data, which allows Mintos to assess the Users interests, to determine which Services are most suitable for the User, to analyse the User’s activity and to segment the User into a certain category.

For the purpose specified above, the User’s data is processed by Mintos and our cooperation partners that provide server, IT, email and message delivery platform services.

Mintos processes User’s personal data until the User withdraws the consent to receive informational materials or, in some cases, when the necessity to keep evidence that consent has been received is no longer in force. Withdrawing consent for receiving informational materials does not affect the consent given to process information obtained through cookies.

3.5. Service quality control

On the basis of the legitimate interest of Mintos to improve the quality of the Services, Mintos, within the aim to evaluate and control the quality of the Services, processes at least the Communication Data when communicating with the User.

For the purpose specified above, the User’s data is processed by Mintos and our cooperation partners that provide server, IT and call recording services.

3.6. Compilation of statistical data

On the basis of the legitimate interest of Mintos to compile statistical data regarding the Services used by the Users, to improve the Service quality and to develop Services, Mintos, with the aim to analyse information related to the provision of the Services, processes summarised information regarding the User’s Data, Contact Information and Transaction Data.

For the purpose specified above, the User’s data is processed by Mintos and our cooperation partner that provides server, IT and analytical services. Based on the received personal data, cooperation partners cannot identify the particular User.

 **4\. Transfer of information to third parties**

Mintos and our cooperation partners process the User’s personal data within the European Economic Area (hereinafter – EEA).

In accordance with Clause 13.3. of the Agreement Mintos has a right to disclose the User’s data to the entities specified below:

  * to any person related to the fulfilment of commitments arising to Mintos from the Agreement (including to communications service providers, payment intermediaries, credit institutions, IT service providers, etc.);
  * to the parent company of Mintos, its governing enterprise and any enterprises dependent on the governing enterprise, other companies or enterprises, which directly or indirectly have obtained a significant share in the share capital of Mintos or in which Mintos has obtained direct or indirect participation, insofar as such information is necessary for the performance of functions delegated to them;
  * to outsourced service providers that Mintos has engaged in the provision of services arising from the Agreement, insofar as such information is necessary for the performance of functions delegated to them;
  * to personal data processors, the supervisor whereof is Mintos, insofar as such information is necessary for the performance of functions delegated to them;
  * upon handing over (transferring) a Claim to third parties;
  * to a third party, who is taking debt collection steps to recover debt from the User (such as debt collectors, lawyers, court bailiffs, insolvency administrators, etc.);
  * to Mintos legal, accounting, or auditing service providers, ensuring that the said persons have undertaken not to divulge such information.

In the cases specified by law, Mintos is obligated to disclose the User’s personal data to state authorities.

Mintos does not disclose any personal data to state authorities or third parties without a legal basis. When delegating certain functions of Mintos to personal data processors, Mintos undertakes to guarantee appropriate technical and organisational security measures to ensure that the personal data processor upholds security standards that are not lower than the security standards set by Mintos.

 **5\. Where and how we store your information**

The data that we collect from you will be transferred to and stored at a destination inside the EEA. All information you provide to us is stored securely on our servers or servers of our partners. The information is encrypted.

Unfortunately, the transmission of information via the internet is not completely secure. Even though we will do our best to protect your personal data, we cannot fully guarantee the security of your data transmitted to us; therefore, transmission is at your own risk. Once we have received your information, we will use procedures and security features to try to prevent unauthorised access.

The access to your personal information within Mintos is limited to those employees who have a good business reason to access or know this information. This is achieved through both technical solutions and physical access rights, as well as proper training and education of our employees who have built appropriate safeguards.

 **6\. Length of retention of information**

All User related information, including information that is stored in the Virtual Account and all communications with Mintos, is stored as evidence confirming the identity of the User, conclusion of the Agreement, transactions made and fulfilment of the Agreement and is kept until the fulfilment of the Agreement, the data is no longer necessary to provide Services, the data storage timeframe or limitation period for legal proceedings established by the laws and regulations of the Republic of Latvia expires, whichever occurs later. Below is a summary of some key considerations how long each piece of information is kept:

For accounting purposes, Mintos stores the User’s personal data in connection with the concluded and fulfilled Agreement for no less than 5 years after the conclusion of the Agreement.

For anti-money laundering and terrorist financing prevention purposes Mintos stores the User’s data in connection with verifying the identity of the User and the origin of the funds (including a copy of an identity document and all Communication Data) for 5 years after the conclusion of the Agreement.

The limitation period for legal proceedings is 10 years in accordance with the Civil law of the Republic of Latvia. Due to the fact that Transaction Data is interconnected with the provision of Services, there may be situations where the Transaction data is stored for a longer period of time in order to provide services to other users.

The Communication Data is retained for at least 1 (one) month up to 3 (three) years, depending on whether the Communication Data contains relevant information regarding the performance of the Agreement or the provision of Services (for example, the provisions of the Agreement are changed, or the Customer submits a complaint about the quality of Services).

 **7\. Your rights related to personal information**

General approach

Mintos respects the User’s rights to access, manage and control the personal data that Mintos processes. Once Mintos receives a User’s request to exercise any of the rights listed below, Mintos will review the User’s request and provide a response without undue delay and in any event within one month of receipt of the request. This time period may be extended if the User’s request is complex or if due to the amount of received requests Mintos cannot prepare a reply within the previously set time limit. In this case Mintos informs the User about the extension of the time limit for preparing a reply to the User’s request and indicates the specific term for preparing a reply.

Should the User wish to exercise any of the rights listed below, the User can do so by submitting a request in one of the following ways:

  * by sending an electronic request to [support@mintos.com](mailto:support@mintos.com);
  * by sending a signed request to Skanstes iela 50, Riga LV-1013, Latvia.

An authorised person can submit a request on behalf of the User, provided that a valid power of attorney is enclosed with the request.

Mintos reserves the right to request additional information from the User in order to verify the identity of the person, who has sent the request, and to protect the User’s data from being disclosed to unauthorised persons.

The User has the right to access the personal data free of charge. However, if the User’s requests are manifestly unfounded or excessive, Mintos retains the right to charge a reasonable fee or to refuse to act on the request.

Below is a summary of User’s specific rights.

7.1. Right of access

The User is entitled to receive information on whether or not Mintos processes the User’s personal data, and, if Mintos processes said personal data, request a copy of the User’s personal data undergoing processing.

The User has the right to obtain the following information:

  * purposes of the processing;
  * categories of personal data being processed;
  * personal data recipients or categories of such recipients;
  * length of time the data will be stored (or criteria for determining the period);
  * User’s rights in connection to the data processing;
  * available information on the data source (if the personal data was not obtained from the User);
  * existence of automated decision-making.

7.2. Right to rectification, to the extent possible

The User is entitled to request Mintos to rectify the User’s inaccurate or incorrect personal data. Mintos also provides the User with the option to rectify data in the Virtual Account, however not all data may be rectified through this channel. We will need to verify that the amended data is true and accurate.

7.3. Right to erasure, to the extent possible

The User is entitled to request Mintos to erase the User’s data. This right can be exercised if one of the following grounds applies:

  * purposes of the processing have been reached;
  * personal data are no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which they were collected or otherwise processed;
  * User withdraws the given consent;
  * User objects to the processing;
  * personal data has been unlawfully processed;
  * personal data has to be erased for compliance with a legal obligation.

Mintos reserves the right to reject the request to erase the User’s personal data if there is a legitimate legal ground for doing so, for example, to comply with a legal obligation which requires processing, to establish, exercise or defend legal claims, or for statistical purposes, providing appropriate technical and organisational security measures. 

7.4. Right to the restriction of processing

The User is entitled to request Mintos to restrict processing if one of the following grounds applies:

  * User contests the accuracy of the personal data, for a period that enables Mintos to verify the accuracy of the personal data;
  * processing is unlawful, and the User requests restriction opposed to the erasure of the personal data;
  * Mintos no longer needs the User’s personal data, but the personal data is necessary for the User to establish, exercise or defend legal claims;
  * User has objected to processing pending the verification whether the legitimate grounds for processing of Mintos override those of the User.

Upon restricting the processing of the User’s personal data, Mintos will only process the User’s personal data after receiving consent from the User, or for the establishment, exercise or defence of legal claims or for the protection of the rights of another natural or legal person or for reasons of important public interest. This does not apply to storing personal data.

7.5. Right to object to the processing of personal data

The User is entitled to object to the personal data processing activities concerning direct marketing or which are based on Mintos legitimate interests but given the basis of the User’s particular situation they want to object to processing on this ground.

7.6. Right to data portability, to the extent possible

The User is entitled to request Mintos to receive and transfer the User’s personal data to the User or another data controller. The User can exercise this right insofar as the data has been provided by the User based on consent or a contract and the processing is carried out by automated means.

This right also applies to raw data that has been provided by the User, relates to the User’s activities or result from observation of the User, for example, activity logs, history of website usage. However, this does not apply to data that Mintos creates, for example, User profiles created by analysing the raw data, risk assessments to comply with anti-money laundering rules.

7.7. Right to withdraw consent

The User is entitled to withdraw previously given consent at any time via the Virtual Account. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent.  This right applies to receiving commercial notices and overviews from Mintos.

For withdrawing consent regarding cookies please visit Privacy Policy [Cookies section](https://www.mintos.com/en/cookie-policy/).

7.8. Right to submit a complaint to the national personal data protection authority

In case of any uncertainty related to your personal data, you are welcome to contact Mintos and we will seek to provide you with an answer or find a solution to your issue. However, if you believe we cannot find the solution, the User is entitled to submit a complaint to the national personal data protection authority regarding data processing activities conducted by Mintos.

The contact information of the national personal data protection authority of the Republic of Latvia:

Data State Inspectorate, Blaumaņa iela 11/13-15, Riga LV-1011, Latvia, phone: +371 67223131, email: [info@dvi.gov.lv](mailto:info@dvi.gov.lv).

7.9. Right to contact Mintos and obtain additional information on the processing of personal data

The User is entitled to contact Mintos at any time and obtain additional information regarding processing activities.

 **8\. Changes in the Privacy Policy**

Mintos has the right to make changes to the Privacy Policy at any time by posting them on the Portal, as well as by informing the Users individually by sending them an email. Any version of the Privacy Policy that is published on this Portal replaces all previous versions of the Policy and takes effect immediately upon posting or from the effective date as indicated.

Original version: 13.04.2015

Site updated: 13.12.2018
